Raymond Flores

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile

Senior Software Engineer with 7+ years in development, design, and testing. Proficient in tools such as Node.js, Express, React, Redux, and PostgreSQL. Experience mentoring and code reviewing junior developers on web application development standards and best practices. Developed/integrated RESTful APIs and designed/developed responsive websites. Experience in agile and scrum methodologies. Exceptional problem solver and ability to quickly master a new technology, skill, or role.

Employment History

Software Engineer, Boom Sports, Remote

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer II, Ticketmaster, Pharr, TX

JANUARY 2019 - JULY 2020

- Replaced legacy production app with a Dockerized React/Redux app that had increased load speeds of 87%, code base was 10x smaller mostly due to table-driven architecture and reusable components, real-time error reporting, and increased code readability.
- Built multiple internal tools that increased operations efficiency between 20-60%.
- Automated and digitalized business flows that were previously done on paper. This saved company tremendous amounts in time and costs for paper.

Senior Backend Engineer, Justuno, Austin, TX

APRIL 2018 - JANUARY 2019

- Responsible for app store integrations to Shopify, Bigcommerce, and Cloudflare, which allowed for having Justuno more accessible and being a one click install for e-commerce stores on these platforms. Resulted in an increase of daily downloads.
- Developed push notifications as a service using Node/Express and built a
 user dashboard React) that allowed Justuno clients to send customized push
 notifications to their customers who opted in.
- Automated testing and unit testing using Selenium, NightWatch, Mocha, and Chai. Developed an Oauth 2.0 Server for 3rd party applications to authenticate with Justuno
- Wrote scripts to update/fix hundreds of thousands of data points
- Used React Components, React Router, Webpack, and Redux to build front end and used ES6, Promises, Async/Await

Lead Developer, Pokersports, Austin, TX

OCTOBER 2016 - APRIL 2018

- Responsible for all technical development of PokerSports, Real-Time Fantasy Sports Multiplayer Card Game FantasyStud Web App), and FantasyStud Mobile App
- Integrating 3rd party services with our products like PayPal Merchant API for deposits and withdrawals, SendGrid API for emails and mass emails, FantasyData for real-time sports stats.
- Building and setting up servers using CentOS, Ubuntu, Bash, NGINX, Apache2, and PM2. Automating builds and other tasks using GULP and Cron jobs to run timely scripts in NodeJS or Bash.
- Managing a team of 2 Junior Developers. Delegated tasks to them and code reviewed their work. Automated browser testing & unit testing using NightWatchJS, Selenium, and Mocha

Full Stack Engineer, Bloxmob, Austin, TX

Details

(956) 789-3046 raymondfflores@gmail.com

Links

<u>Portfolio</u>

Github

LinkedIn

React and Redux (Certificate)

NodeJS (Certificate)

Typescript (Certificate)

React Native (Certificate)

GraphQL (Certificate)

Modern GraphQL (Certificate)

Skills

JavaScript

React

Redux

Node.js

Express

Docker

SQL

NoSQL Typescript

React Native

GraphQL

- Developed a platform that lets users create mobile apps without knowing how to code.
- Continuously built and integrated new features. Conducted code reviews and maintained and optimized current infrastructure. End-to-End (E2E) testing solutions.
- Front-end development using AngularJS, Back-end development using Node.js, and other tools including Ionic, PostgreSQL, Gulp, and Require.js.
- Built analytics for business intelligence and market outreach.

Software Developer I, Think Tech Labs, Austin, TX

AUGUST 2015 - JANUARY 2016

- Developed software solutions for real estate agents on Salesforce Platform.
- Collaborated with business analysts, product managers, and other engineers to incorporate functionality into residential product.
- Front-end development using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, VisualForce pages, and Lightning Components. Also maintained existing tools and infrastructure as necessary. Conducted unit tests for server side code. Documented software functionality. Worked on a 4-8 member team to continuously build and integrate new features.

Full Stack Developer, Perficientur, McAllen, TX

JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2015

- Developed custom business software for clients that provided automated workflows, valuable data, business intelligence, key performance indicators, and automated alerts in real time.
- Rapid prototyping for client feedback, developed and used RESTful APIs, agile based projects, data-driven applications.
- Developed and maintained web application systems using Node.js, AngularJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Used AngularJS for Single Page Application development.
- Managed a team of 3-4 programmers and designed solutions for our projects.

Full Stack Developer, JPT Consulting & Services, McAllen, TX

JANUARY 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

- Collaborated with a team of software engineers and hardware engineers to develop a resource monitoring system (Safe Wireless Remote Sensor) for oil, gas, & water. Main development tools used were Node.js, AngularJS, Express, PostgreSQL, and Redis.
- Rapid prototyping for client feedback, developed and used RESTful APIs, agile based projects, data-driven applications and Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Worked on many other local projects to acquire revenue for research &
 development of SafeWireless Remote Sensor. These projects were mainly
 for local businesses to help optimize and digitize their business process
 or cognitive model of a process. Also provided analytics to help provide
 information for better business decision- making.

Education

Bachelors, Computer Science, University of Texas - Pan American, Edinburg

AUGUST 2011 - AUGUST 2015

GPA: 3.41